<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

	<ModMetaData>
  
		<name>Beta-humanoids</name>
  
		<author>Foggy Morning</author>
  
		<url>https://github.com/FoggyMorning/Rimworld-Betas</url>
  
		<supportedVersions><li>1.0</li></supportedVersions>

		<description>
		A Beta Class Humanoid Lifeform. Part human and part animal. The property of the Corporation that created them.
		
		Their job: Justification and Pacification of new worlds. Find exploitable resources and elimniate dangerous indigenous lifeforms.
		
		The Galactic Workers Alliance secured semi-human rights for Betas through a series of punishing strikes, forcing the Corporations to allow the Betas to buyback the cost of their birth and training.
		
		Now some "Betas" have managed to purchase their freedom and begun to make their way to the Rim.

		[H1]What does this mod do?[/H1]
		The "Beta-humanoids" mod gives a chance for the Beta-humanoids races to be available at Colony start (PlayerColony and PlayerTribe), and to later appear as refugees, wanderers, and slaves. 		
		I tried to make the Beta's heads look correct with the vanilla hats and helmets, however the Powered Marine Helmet would not work, and I had to make new textures for it to allow for (short) snouts. 
        Includes an Options menu where you can set the chance for each Beta race type to appear.
		
		Races added:
		Elephants and Hogs Betas have a tusk attack; Bears, Lynx, Fox, and Raccoon Betas have claw and bite attacks; and Gazelle and Male Elks have horn attacks. All damage values are based on the animals they are created from.

		Bear:
			Advantages:
				Larger than humans with increased health. Increased comfortable temperature range. 
			Disadvantages:
				Works slower, increased chance for Greedy and Gourmand negative traits.

		Camels:
			Advantages:
				Comfortable at higher temps. Lowered hunger rate. Increased chance of Ascetic trait.
			Disadvantages:
				Increased Chance of Abrasive trait.
		
		Elephants:
			Advantages:
				Much larger than humans with increased health.  Increased social impact. Slightly increased chance of Good Memory and Kind traits.
			Disadvantages:
				Increased hunger rate.
		
		Elk:
			Advantages:
				Larger than humans.  Move slightly faster. Males have much higher chance to get the Brawler trait to represent the antlers.  
			Disadvantages:
				Increased chance to have the Nervous trait.
		
		Fox:
			Advantages:
			 	Research slightly faster.  Chance to get the Night owl trait.
			Disadvantages:
				Smaller than humans with decreased health. Slight chance to get the Too Smart trait. 
		
		Gazelle:
			Advantages:
			 	Move very fast.  Slight chance for Brawler and Nimble traits.
			Disadvantages:
				Smaller than humans with decreased health. Greatly reduced mining speed. 
		
		Lynx:
			Advantages:
			 	Increased movement speed. Chance to gain Night owl trait.
			Disadvantages:
				Smaller than humans with decreased health. Chance to gain the Psychopath trait.
		
		Hog:
			Advantages:
			 	Chance to gain the FastLearner trait.
			Disadvantages:
				Smaller than humans with decreased health. Chance to gain the Cannibal trait.
		
		Raccoon:
			Advantages:
			 	Doesn't get bad thoughts for eating kibble or insect meat.  100% chance to gain the Night owl trait.
			Disadvantages:
				Smaller than humans with decreased health. Decreased movement speed. 
		
		Wolf:
			Advantages:
			 	Increased move speed.  Increased chance to gain the Psychic Sensitivity 1 trait.
			Disadvantages:
			 	Increased chance to gain the Psychic Sensitivity 1 trait.
		


		Inspired by the "BeastMan Tribals" mod.   https://steamcommunity.com/id/joeglass/myworkshopfiles/?appid=294100
		The "BeastMan Tribals" mod creates Beastmen that can appear as tribal factions. 
		Both mods can be active at the same time.

		Fluff inspired by the long defunct RPG "Justifiers".  https://rpggeek.com/rpg/1185/justifiers-rpg
		
		</description>
	
</ModMetaData>