<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

	<ModMetaData>
  
		<name>Beta-humanoids</name>
  
		<author>Foggy Morning</author>
  
		<url>https://github.com/FoggyMorning/Rimworld-Betas</url>
  
		<supportedVersions><li>1.0</li></supportedVersions>

		<description>
		Inspired by the "BeastMan Tribals" mod.  
		Includes new art and makes them only available to the New Arrivals faction.
		New Art for the Powered Marine Helmet to allow for snouts.


		Bear:
			Advantages:
				Larger than humans with increased health. Increased comfortable temperature range. 
			Disadvantages:
				Works slower, increased chance for Greedy and Gourmand negative traits.

		Camels:
			Advantages:
				Comfortable at higher temps. Lowered hunger rate. Increased chance of Ascetic trait.
			Disadvantages:
				Increased Chance of Abrasive trait.
		
		Elephants:
			Advantages:
				Much larger than humans with increased health.  Increased social impact. Slightly increased chance of Good Memory and Kind traits.
			Disadvantages:
				Doubled hunger rate.
		
		Elk:
			Advantages:
				Larger than humans.  Move slightly faster. Males have much higher chance to get the Brawler trait to represent the antlers.  
			Disadvantages:
				Increased chance to have the Nervous trait.
		
		Fox:
			Advantages:
			 	Research slightly faster.  Chance to get the Night owl trait.
			Disadvantages:
				Smaller than humans with decreased health. Slight chance to get the Too Smart trait. 
		
		Gazelle:
			Advantages:
			 	Move very fast.  Slight chance for Brawler and Nimble traits.
			Disadvantages:
				Smaller than humans with decreased health. Greatly reduced mining speed. 
		
		Lynx:
			Advantages:
			 	Increased movement speed. Chance to gain Night owl trait.
			Disadvantages:
				Smaller than humans with decreased health. Chance to gain the Psychopath trait.
		
		Hog:
			Advantages:
			 	Chance to gain the FastLearner trait.
			Disadvantages:
				Smaller than humans with decreased health. Chance to gain the Cannibal trait.
		
		Raccoon:
			Advantages:
			 	100% chance to gain the Night owl trait.
			Disadvantages:
				Smaller than humans with decreased health. Decreased movement speed. 
		
		Wolf:
			Advantages:
			 	Increased move speed.  Increased chance to gain the Psychic Sensitivity 1 trait.
			Disadvantages:
			 	Increased chance to gain the Psychic Sensitivity 1 trait.

		</description>
	
</ModMetaData>